♪ In the face of turmoil ♪
♪ 面对混乱 ♪
♪ Its roots hold firmly ♪
♪ 它的根牢牢地扎根 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 来到这片土地 ♪
♪ Searching for the waves ♪
♪ 寻找海浪 ♪
♪ My leaves flutter ♪
♪ 我的叶子飘动 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 地平线 ♪
♪ Dealing from afar ♪
♪ 远方交易 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 在世界的尽头 ♪
♪ It's eternity ♪
♪ 这是永恒 ♪
♪ When we meet and then part ♪
♪ 当我们相遇然后分离 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other and then move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖 然后离开时 ♪
♪ I never forgot it ♪
♪ 我从未忘记 ♪
♪ By cutting the shine of swords ♪
♪ 削减剑的光芒 ♪
♪ Through the dappled sky ♪
♪ 穿过斑驳的天空 ♪
♪ Dreams that fall ♪
♪ 坠落的梦想 ♪
♪ Shatter in the wind ♪
♪ 随风破碎 ♪
♪ As the wind cuts through the waves ♪
♪ 风破浪而过 ♪
♪ Watch thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 观看数千支蜡烛交叉 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 辽阔的土地和无边的海洋 ♪
♪ Armor and red robes flying high ♪
♪ 铠甲和红袍高飞 ♪
♪ Against bitterness, intense emotions and joyful adventures ♪
♪ 对抗苦涩、 强烈的情绪和快乐的冒险 ♪
♪ I just wish you were by my side ♪
♪ 我只希望你在我身边 ♪
♪ Make the most of what life has to offer ♪
♪ 充分利用生活所提供的一切 ♪
♪ Like tall trees with interconnected roots, I will accompany you to the ends ♪
♪ 就像根相连的大树一样 ，我会陪你走到尽头 ♪
♪ Watching the fireflies land on our shoulders ♪
♪ 看着萤火虫落在 我们的肩上 ♪
♪ Don't regret it, there are no doubts in this world ♪
♪ 不要后悔，这世界上没有疑虑 ♪
= Wonders of love =
=爱的奇迹=
= Episode 22 =
=第22集=
Anyone here?
这里有人吗？
There is someone there?
那里有人吗？
How could you tie me here for three days and three nights?
你怎么能把我绑在这里 三天三夜？
Who did it?
谁干的？
Anyone here?
这里有人吗？
Señor,
先生，
I'm going to die of thirst
我快要渴死了
give me some water, please.
请给我一些水。
Señor,
先生，
why guys
为什么伙计们
bind this tree?
绑定这棵树？
As long as you leave me free,
只要你让我自由
I give you
我给你
all my family assets.
我所有的家庭资产。
The Cui Army led by my uncle is also
我舅舅率领的崔军也是
known as the Army of Victory.
被誉为胜利之军。
Never...
绝不...
¿You?
你？
¿ Cui Lin?
¿ Cui Lin?
He didn't die, huh?
他没有死，是吗？
I'm not Cui Lin.
我不是崔琳。
Lin,
林,
I'm glad you're still alive.
我很高兴你还活着。
I'm happy to see you alive!
我很高兴看到你还活着！
I already told you.
我已经告诉过你。
I'm not Cui Lin.
我不是崔琳。
Yeah.
是的。
No.
不。
You are not Cui Lin.
你不是崔琳。
My name is Liu Chengfeng.
My name is Liu Chengfeng.
Have you remembered that?
你还记得吗？
Yes, I do.
是的，我愿意。
You are Young Master Liu Chengfeng.
You are Young Master Liu Chengfeng.
Master Liu.
刘老师。
Young Master Liu.
刘少爷。
Young Master Liu, I beg you.
刘少爷，求你了。
I'm willing to do anything.
我愿意做任何事。
Young Master Liu.
刘少爷。
Young Master Liu, trust me.
刘少爷，相信我。
Please free me,
请释放我，
Young Master Liu.
刘少爷。
they,
他们，
¿ La gente de Jieshuo?
¿ La gente de Jieshuo?
You are not Cui Lin.
你不是崔琳。
You are definitely not Cui Lin.
你绝对不是崔琳。
The Cui family has a deep resentment against the Jieshuo people.
崔家 对界朔人有着很深的怨恨。
Anyone with the last name Cui
姓崔的人
He will never make acquaintances with the people of Jieshuo.
他永远不会与界朔的人结识。
It's true.
这是真的。
Soy Liu Chengfeng.
Soy Liu Chengfeng.
I'm not Cui Lin.
我不是崔琳。
Do you know what you swallowed just now?
你知道 你刚才吞下的是什么吗？
It is a poison pill manufactured by
这是一种毒丸，由
the witch doctors of Jieshuo.
界说巫医。
If you don't follow my instructions,
如果你不听从我的指示
If you don't take the antidote on time,
如果不 按时服用解药
your body will break.
你的身体会崩溃。
Young Master Liu!
刘少爷！
Please don't hold it against me!
请不要以此来反对我！
I'm willing to do anything for you
我愿意为你做任何事
as long as you let me live!
只要你让我活下去！
Young Master Liu!
刘少爷！
I'm willing to do anything!
我什么都愿意做！
As long as you obey my will
只要你服从我的意志
and follow my instructions,
并按照我的指示进行操作，
I will give you the antidote.
我会给你解药。
Thank you, Young Master Liu.
谢谢刘少爷。
Taozi,
Taozi,
I gathered these
我收集了这些
in the mountains for you.
在山里为你。
They are nice.
他们很好。
They smell very good.
它们闻起来很香。
By the way,
顺便一提，
How is Mr. Shiqi?
世奇先生怎么样？
Don't mention that.
别提那个了。
Great General
大将军
He has freed him from jail.
他把他从监狱里释放了。
However, he gave him 30 lashes
然而，他却给了他30下鞭子
(Wolong) according to military rules.
（卧龙） 按军规。
That?
那？
30 lashes?
30根睫毛？
However,
然而，
lord Qin
秦王
He is a tough man indeed.
他确实是一个硬汉。
I was not willing
我不甘心
pray to Great General
向大将军祈福
even after receiving all that punishment.
即使在受到 所有这些惩罚之后。
That's the way
就是这个方法
he is.
他是。
He will never give up until death.
他至死都不会放弃。
Actually, Great General
其实大将军
It's soft too.
它也很软。
Lord Qin wouldn't need to suffer so much
秦王不需要受这么大的苦
if you made an exception in the first place.
如果你一开始就破例了。
Since you collected these,
自从你收集了这些，
You should have some too.
你也应该有一些。
Alright.
好吧。
You can have them all if you want.
如果你愿意的话，你可以全部拥有。
This is good.
这很好。
GOOD.
好的。
I see.
我懂了。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
The entire Cui army
整个崔军
acts the same way.
行为方式相同。
Hard on the outside, but soft on the inside.
外面坚硬， 但里面柔软。
Be careful, I'm very fierce.
小心点，我很凶的。
Yes Yes. You are fierce.
是的是的。你很凶猛。
Great General,
伟大的将军，
We have already cleared the front of the battlefield.
我们已经清理了 战场正面。
We brought the prisoners back.
我们把囚犯带回来了。
Now, we are doing an inventory check.
现在，我们正在进行库存检查。
Yeah,
是的，
Shouldn't I have done it?
我不应该这样做吗？
Padre,
神父，
what's happening?
发生了什么？
When you were born,
当你出生时，
I told the imperial court
我告诉朝廷
that you were a boy
你是个男孩
When you grew up,
当你长大后，
Liu Chengfeng replaced you as Cui Lin
Liu Chengfeng replaced you as Cui Lin
and he became my son.
他成了我的儿子。
You are a lady.
你是一位女士。
But you ride horses
但你骑马
and fight battles at my side.
并与我并肩作战。
How I can
我怎么能
get a husband in the future?
将来找个老公吗？
Those who are willing to marry you
那些愿意嫁给你的人
It will definitely have all kinds of defects.
肯定会有各种各样的缺陷。
Forget about you,
忘记你，
I won't even like it.
我什至不会喜欢它。
Father, what are you saying?
父亲，你在说什么？
I like going to war.
我喜欢去打仗。
I like to live this way.
我喜欢这样的生活。
There are many men in the world.
世界上有很多男人。
I can do everything
我什么都可以做
They do it.
他们做到了。
Why should I get married then?
那我为什么要结婚呢？
You are a lady after all.
你毕竟是一位女士。
They will get married and give birth eventually.
他们最终会结婚 并生子。
Actually,
实际上，
feng is pretty good too.
枫也不错啊
He...
他...
Padre,
神父，
the world is huge
世界很大
and vast.
和广阔。
There are many places
有很多地方
that I haven't been yet.
我还没有去过。
There are many things
有很多事情
I want to experience it for myself.
我想亲自体验一下。
Yes, get married and give birth
是的，结婚生子
It is one of the experiences,
也是一种体验，
There is nothing wrong with omitting it.
省略它并没有什么错。
It's just one of thousands of experiences
这只是数以千计的经历之一
i will experience
我会经历
Someday I'm going to grow old.
总有一天我会变老。
Eventually we will have to part ways.
最终我们将不得不分道扬镳。
By then, you will be alone.
到那时，你将孤身一人。
I'll feel too embarrassed
我会觉得太丢人
to face your mother in the afterlife.
来世面对你的母亲。
Padre,
神父，
I have driven
我已经开车了
a happy and carefree life.
幸福无忧的生活。
When you see the mother
当你看到妈妈的时候
in the other life,
在另一个生命里，
just tell her
只是告诉她
that this was my favorite way of life.
这是我最喜欢的生活方式。
I think that
我觉得
mom will be happy
妈妈会很高兴的
when he hears it.
当他听到的时候。
There is nothing more satisfying
没有什么比这更令人满意的了
That leaving your daughter leads a happy and carefree life, right?
离开女儿 就过着幸福无忧无虑的生活吧？
Great General,
伟大的将军，
The scouts we sent have discovered a suspect.
我们派出的侦察员 发现了一名嫌疑人。
They found Cui Li's footprints.
他们发现了崔莉的脚印。
Don't let
不要让
Lieutenant He finds out.
何中尉发现了。
Deploy our troops.
部署我们的军队。
I'm going there personally.
我亲自去那里。
Yes, Great General.
是的，大将军。
Young Master Liu.
刘少爷。
Cui Yi will be here later.
崔毅稍后会来。
Do you still remember
你还记得吗
what do you have to say?
你有什么要说的？
Yes, Young Master Liu.
是啊，刘少爷。
Yes I remember my verses.
是的，我记得我的诗句。
Young Master Liu,
刘少爷，
Yes, I do
是的，我愿意
play my part in your act,
在你的表演中扮演我的角色，
will you give me the antidote
你能给我解药吗
so I can survive?
这样我才能活下去？
Young Master Liu,
刘少爷，
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I will definitely do my part well.
我一定会做好自己的部分。
Yeah.
是的。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
Reporting!
报告！
Great General, we have surrounded the forest.
伟大的将军， 我们已经包围了森林。
Cui Li has escaped into the forest with his men.
崔立 带着手下逃入森林。
It completely surrounds the forest.
它完全包围了森林。
Don't let him escape.
别让他逃走。
Yeah!
是的！
Do not get close to me!
别靠近我！
Everyone, stay!
大家留下来！
I'll kill him if you take one step closer!
你再靠近一步我就杀了他！
Do not come here!
不要来这里！
Comes back!
回来！
Uncle.
叔叔。
Do not move!
不要动！
Uncle!
叔叔！
Man, I had no choice!
伙计，我别无选择！
Let go.
松手。
Uncle,
叔叔，
I had no choice!
我别无选择！
Dude, don't come near me!
兄弟，别靠近我！
Don't force me to do it!
别强迫我这么做！
Lower your sword.
放下你的剑。
He is still my nephew.
他仍然是我的侄子。
But,
但，
You can't forgive yourself for what you've done.
你无法原谅自己 所做的事。
Uncle,
叔叔，
I had no choice!
我别无选择！
Li Ni forced me to do this!
李妮是逼我这么做的！
He said he would kill me if I didn't kill Lin!
他说我 不杀林他就杀了我！
That's why I put on an act
这就是我表演的原因
and forced Lin to jump into the river.
并强迫林某跳入河中。
But once they were gone,
但一旦他们走了，
I went downstream
我顺流而下
and saved Cui Lin.
并救了崔琳。
I even treated his wounds!
我还帮他处理了伤口！
Uncle!
叔叔！
Let go!
松手！
Dude, don't make me!
兄弟，别逼我！
Fuego.
富埃戈。
I win!
我赢了！
Padre,
神父，
because I have
因为我有
to practice this all the time?
一直练习这个？
Because you are my daughter.
因为你是我的女儿。
The people of Jieshuo are ruthless.
界朔之人，心狠手辣。
If they take you hostage one day,
如果 有一天他们把你劫为人质
I hope I can save you
我希望我能拯救你
with my bow and arrow.
用我的弓和箭。
Come here.
过来。
Father, can I join too?
爸爸，我也可以加入吗？
Clear.
清除。
You are my son too.
你也是我的儿子。
We can do this training
我们可以做这个培训
for as long as you want.
只要你愿意。
Thanks, Dad!
感谢爸爸！
Why do you thank me? Come, let me show you.
你为什么要感谢我？ 来吧，让我给你展示一下。
Fuego.
富埃戈。
Untie him.
把他解开。
- Yes Yes.
- 是的 是的。
I already told you.
我已经告诉过你。
could save you
可以救你
if you step on the sword.
如果你踩到剑上。
But,
但，
I have to take you down according to military rules.
我必须 按照军事规则把你打倒。
they,
他们，
What did you say?
你说什么？
they...
他们...
Your Highness.
殿下。
Why don't you let me do it?
你为什么不让我做呢？
You should resume your work.
你应该继续你的工作。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I'll make sure this soup doesn't boil over too much.
我会确保这汤不会煮得太沸。
But the heat is too much...
但是热量实在是太大了...
Taozi.
Taozi.
Come here.
过来。
It's not that. I...
这并不是说。我...
Don't scratch it.
别刮伤它。
will never heal
永远不会痊愈
if you keep scratching it.
如果你继续抓它。
But you don't help me apply medicine.
但你不帮我 涂药。
I can't reach it myself.
我自己达不到。
Of course it will sting.
当然会刺痛。
I'm doing it to teach you a lesson.
我这样做是为了给你一个教训。
I'll see if they dare to repeat it next time.
我倒要看看他们 下次还敢不敢重蹈覆辙。
Next time? No, thanks.
下次？不，谢谢。
It's hard to say.
很难说。
You are a dense man.
你是个厚重的人。
I am sure that Father
我确信父亲
He will be angry when he sees you.
他一看到你就会生气。
Maybe I'll hit you again next time.
也许下次我会再打你。
We can talk about it then.
到时候我们可以谈谈。
I think that
我觉得
The soup is almost ready.
汤快好了。
Try it.
尝试一下。
Let me get a big one.
让我来一个大的。
Blueberries.
蓝莓。
And red dates.
还有红枣。
All finished.
全部完成。
Give him an oportunity.
给他一个机会。
How is? It is sweet?
怎么？是甜的吗？
It's pretty good.
这个很不错。
You should let me try it then.
那你应该让我试试。
There's still a lot.
还有很多。
Put on a bowl.
放在碗上。
Did I try your medicine to see if it was bitter before you?
我在你面前试过你的药 苦不苦？
Don't you think you should let me try how sweet the soup is?
你不觉得你应该让我尝尝 汤有多甜吗？
Let me try it.
让我尝试一下。
Yeah,
是的，
come to my room.
来我的房间。
- Young Master. - Yeah.
- 少爷。 - 是的。
Young master, you are awake.
少爷，你醒了。
Yeah.
是的。
I'm not dreaming, am I?
我不是在做梦吧？
I could actually see you again.
我真的可以再次见到你。
Yeah.
是的。
Young Master, we are all happy
少爷，我们都很幸福
that you returned safely.
你安全回来了。
This is great.
这很棒。
Yeah,
是的，
we can be together again.
我们可以再次在一起。
Padre.
神父。
Do not get up.
不要起来。
You have to rest and recover.
你必须休息并恢复。
Padre,
神父，
Cui Li captured Shu as well.
崔厉也攻克了蜀国。
I don't know where he hid it.
我不知道他把它藏在哪里了。
I knew it.
我就知道。
He was also rescued.
他也被救了。
Thanks, Dad.
感谢爸爸。
You are my son.
你是我的儿子。
Why are you being so polite now?
你现在怎么这么有礼貌？
Maybe...
或许...
Maybe it's because I've survived a disaster.
也许是因为 我从一场灾难中幸存下来。
I'm still stumped.
我还是很困惑。
I still feel like I'm in dreams.
我仍然感觉自己像在梦中。
You were born with a weak constitution.
你生来体质较弱。
When the doctor reads your pulse,
当医生给你看脉搏时，
he said you were healthier
他说你更健康了
more than before.
比以前更多。
Maybe everything got better
也许一切都会变得更好
after surviving the disaster.
度过灾难后。
Yeah.
是的。
I hope so.
但愿如此。
Your Majesty. Are you trying to kill someone?
陛下。 你想杀人吗？
I'll go on a killing spree
我将继续疯狂杀戮
if you don't come back.
如果你不回来。
My older brother survived a disaster.
我的哥哥在一场灾难中幸存下来。
And, finally we rescued him.
最后我们救了他。
Shouldn't I see him?
我不应该见他吗？
I do not care
我不在乎
If he were your real big brother.
如果他是你真正的大哥就好了。
But it's not like that.
但事实并非如此。
You even made him a set of chess pieces
你还给他做了一套棋子
and your hands hurt.
你的手受伤了。
You always call him Brother.
你总是叫他哥哥。
That?
那？
Don't you have a name?
你没有名字吗？
His real name is Liu Chengfeng.
他的真名是刘乘风。
Although his last name is not Cui,
虽然他不姓崔，
it's my real
这是我的真实的
eldest brother.
大哥。
Either way, I don't like it.
不管怎样，我不喜欢它。
It is disloyal and dishonest.
这是不忠诚和不诚实的。
At that time, he sold Tong Pass outside
当时他在外面卖通关
and caused the death of many soldiers in the Zhenxi Army.
并造成镇西军不少将士死亡。
Besides,
除了，
even
甚至
argued with me
与我争论
because I didn't save him in time.
因为我没有及时救他。
You never acted like this in front of me
你从来没有 在我面前这样表现过
for the good of other people.
为了他人的利益。
Now that it's back,
既然回来了，
you spent so much time checking it.
你花了那么多时间 检查它。
Even if it's your real brother,
就算是你亲弟弟
I think you went to the sea.
我想你是去海边了。
You're so petty.
你真是太小气了
I think I'll tell the kitchen to send you a vat
我想我会告诉厨房 给你送一个大桶
of vinegar to cure you of your jealousy tonight.
今晚用醋来消除你的嫉妒心。
We were interrupted when we had dessert.
当我们吃甜点时，我们被打扰了。
That?
那？
Do you want me to drink vinegar now?
现在要我喝醋吗？
GOOD.
好的。
Drink vinegar with me.
和我一起喝醋吧
Let's try it together.
我们一起来尝试一下吧。
We won't have the chance
我们不会有机会
when Great General Cui is here.
当崔大将军来的时候。
That was an excellent plan.
这是一个很棒的计划。
Cui Li deserves to die.
崔立该死。
Many soldiers died because of him.
许多士兵因他而死。
It also caused Xing's death.
也造成了邢氏的死亡。
I wanted to kill him a long time ago.
我很久以前就想杀了他。
I've kept it alive until now
我一直让它活到现在
to be able to use it fully.
才能充分利用它。
young master,
少爷，
li Ni is in residence.
在Ni是居住地。
Actually?
实际上？
Young Master, you poisoned the lieutenant
少爷，你给中尉下了毒
to lure Li Ni to the residence.
引诱李妮到住处。
However, he did not expect that the Great General
然而他没想到，大将军
to let him take care of Lieutenant Him.
让他照顾贺中尉。
Young master,
少爷，
is Great General
是伟大的将军
going to parade
去游行
lieutenant He to Li Ni?
lieutenant He to Li Ni?
Everyone who stops me from marrying Ying
所有阻止我嫁给英的人
they will have to die.
他们必须死。
Since Li Ni is already here,
既然李妮已经来了，
I'll get rid of him first.
我先除掉他。
Padre,
神父，
were you looking for me?
你在找我吗？
Feng,
冯，
take a sit.
请坐。
Padre,
神父，
Now that you're addressing me by that name,
既然你 用这个名字称呼我，
I feel like I'm not used to it.
我感觉我不太习惯。
Feng, even since you were seriously injured and fell into the water,
枫，既然你受了重伤 ，掉进了水里，
I sent many of my men
我派了很多人去
to look for you
来找你
We can't find you no matter what we do.
无论我们做什么，我们都找不到你。
I thought you were already gone.
我以为你已经走了。
After that, Ying and I
之后我和瑛
Went to pay our respects to you at your grave.
去你的坟墓前表达我们的敬意 。
They reminded me of the past.
他们让我想起了过去。
In the past,
在过去，
I was too selfish.
我太自私了。
Although I asked you
虽然我问过你
If you were willing to be my son when you were young,
如果你小时候愿意做我的儿子
you were still young and callous back then.
那时你还年轻，还冷酷无情。
You couldn't fully understand what I told you.
你无法完全理解 我告诉你的话。
Padre.
神父。
I have decided.
我已决定。
You can call yourself Liu Chengfeng again.
你又可以叫自己 刘乘风了。
However, you will still be my son.
但是，你仍然是我的儿子。
I will tell everyone
我会告诉大家
that you are my adopted son.
你是我的养子。
Padre,
神父，
Are you allowing me to acknowledge my ancestry?
你允许我 承认我的血统吗？
Now,
现在，
ying is all grown up.
莹已经长大了。
She was born as a deliberate girl.
她生来就是一个有思想的女孩。
She doesn't need me to take care of her.
她不需要我照顾她。
you grew up
你长大了
in our residence since he was young.
从小就在我们住处。
Really
真的
I saw you as my son.
我把你当作我的儿子。
I want you to recognize your ancestry.
我希望你能认清你的祖先。
After that,
在那之后，
I will tell the matchmaker
我会告诉媒人
to find a virtuous wife for you
为你找一个贤惠的妻子
and give birth to your descendants.
并生下你的后裔。
In this way, the Liu family
就这样，刘家
They will be able to maintain their lineage.
他们将能够维持他们的血统。
Padre,
神父，
are you abandoning me?
你抛弃我了吗？
Although you are changing your name,
虽然你要改名，
You are still my son.
你仍然是我的儿子。
Padre,
神父，
gracias.
谢谢。
Padre.
神父。
It's time to take your medicine.
是时候吃药了。
Why are you serving me
你为什么要为我服务
with my medicine today?
今天用我的药吗？
Padre,
神父，
serve you
服务你
it is my duty.
这是我的职责。
Padre,
神父，
I'm sure you were worried about me
我确信你很担心我
when I fell into the water after suffering serious injuries.
当我受重伤后掉进水里时。
Even so, you still thought of me
即便如此，你依然想着我
and allowed me to recognize my ancestry.
并让我 认识到我的祖先。
I am really grateful to you.
我真的很感激你。
Although I am not your real son,
虽然我不是你的亲儿子，
in my heart,
在我心里，
padre,
神父，
You will always be my real father.
你永远是我真正的父亲。
So these are the obligations
所以这些是义务
should comply.
应遵守。
In the future,
将来，
I will serve you well.
我会好好为你服务的。
You just recovered from your condition.
你刚刚从病情中恢复过来。
And, you just came back not long ago.
而且，你才刚回来没多久。
You also have to rest and recover.
你还必须休息和恢复。
I will tell Taozi to read your pulse
我叫桃子给你把脉
and prepare some recipes for you after this.
然后为你准备一些食谱。
Thanks, Dad.
感谢爸爸。
Here.
这里。
Father, please take your medicine.
爸爸，请吃药吧。
Be careful. It's hot.
当心。很热。
Greetings,
问候，
great General.
伟大的将军。
Mr. Qin, what do you need?
秦先生，您需要什么？
Great General,
伟大的将军，
I want to discuss
我想讨论
the Changzhou issue with you.
常州问题与你有关。
Changzhou
常州
It is already part of our territory.
它已经是我们领土的一部分。
Lord Qin, if you want to retake Changzhou,
秦大人，你若想 夺回常州，
We will see each other on the battlefield.
我们将在战场上见面。
Great General, you misunderstood me.
大将军，您误会了。
Initially, I wrote a letter to the Cui army
最初，我给崔军写了一封信
to request your help in resolving the emergency in Changzhou.
请求您帮助 解决常州的紧急情况。
Great General, you have stationed your troops in Changzhou.
大将军，您已驻扎 常州了。
Although I came here with my army,
虽然我带着我的军队来到这里，
I wouldn't want
我不想
get involved in a battle.
卷入一场战斗。
Is that so?
是这样吗？
Great General?
大将军？
Great General!
伟大的将军！
Don't let it escape!
别让它逃走！
He hurt the Great General!
他伤了大将军！
¡Dinos!
¡恐龙！
What exactly did you do
你到底做了什么
to the Great General?
给大将军？
I already told you.
我已经告诉过你。
I talked to him
我和他谈过
when he vomited blood and fell unconscious.
当他吐血 并失去知觉时。
That's why I went out to look for help.
这就是我出去寻求帮助的原因。
Why would I seek help?
我为什么要寻求帮助？
If I intend to hurt him?
如果我故意伤害他呢？
You did not go
你没有去
because you know you couldn't escape.
因为你知道 你无法逃脱。
Bring the archers here.
把弓箭手带到这里来。
Don't let him escape.
别让他逃走。
kill him
杀了他
if something happens to the Father.
如果父亲出了什么事。
Great General!
伟大的将军！
Taozi, how are you?
桃子，你怎么样？
Great General?
大将军？
Great General.
伟大的将军。
Great General!
伟大的将军！
kill him
杀了他
avenge Father!
为父报仇！
Wait!
等待！
The truth behind the Great General's murder has not yet been revealed.
大将军被杀的真相 尚未揭晓。
We cannot confirm if he was poisoned or damaged by other methods.
我们无法确认他是否中毒 或被其他方法损坏。
You shouldn't kill him.
你不应该杀他。
Even now, are you still trying to defend him?
事到如今，你还想 维护他吗？
I'm not defending him.
我不是在为他辩护。
My father is barely breathing now.
我父亲现在几乎没有呼吸了。
You must have been under a spell.
你一定是中了咒语了。
Lord Qin will never harm the Great General!
秦王绝对不会伤害大将军！
For the sake of Changzhou,
为了常州，
Mr. Qin
Mr. Qin
will resort to anything.
会采取任何手段。
He is cunning and dishonest.
他狡猾又不诚实。
If we don't kill him,
如果我们不杀他
will escape!
会逃跑！
¡Fuego!
¡ 富埃戈！
¡Deja!
德哈！
Release him!
放开他！
Let go!
松手！
How dare you treat me like this?
你怎么敢这样对待我？
Lieutenant,
中尉，
are you trying to organize a revolt here?
你想在这里组织叛乱吗？
Let go.
松手。
Let go!
松手！
He's gone.
他走了。
With its capacity,
凭借其能力，
I probably won't be able to reach it.
我可能无法 达到它。
So, are you still going to put your sword to my neck?
那么，你还要 把剑架在我脖子上吗？
Someone!
有人！
Lieutenant was tricked by the villain.
中尉被恶棍欺骗了。
And he released the suspect.
然后他释放了嫌疑人。
Send it...
发送...
Send her to the water prison.
把她送进水牢。
Young Master!
少爷！
The life of the Great General is in danger.
大将军的生命处于危险之中。
You must postpone
你必须推迟
my punishment for now.
我现在的惩罚。
Let me first look after the Great General.
我先去看看 大将军。
So, they still knew that Great General's life was in danger?
那么，他们还是知道 大将军有生命危险的吗？
¡Sácala!
萨卡拉！
Take her.
带她去。
Young master,
少爷，
I believe the Great General was poisoned.
我相信大将军是被毒死的。
Lieutenant He, she...
何中尉，她……
I was anxious.
我很着急。
Why don't you let him stay?
你为什么不让他留下来？
Be quiet!
安静！
Young Master.
少爷。
Someone!
有人！
Young Master!
少爷！
Arrest Taozi too.
也逮捕桃子。
His punishment will be announced in due time.
对他的处罚 将在适当的时候公布。
Young Master!
少爷！
How can you...
你怎么...
Where is Mr. Shiqi?
世奇先生在哪里？
He has already escaped.
他已经逃走了。
Where is the lieutenant?
中尉在哪里？
She is under close surveillance. We can't rescue her for now.
她受到严密监视。 我们暂时无法营救她。
We will flee first.
我们先逃走。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Young master, we have brought Lieutenant He here.
少爷， 何中尉被我们带来了。
- Yes, Young Master.
- 是的，少爷。
Yeah,
是的，
you must have suffered.
你一定受过苦了。
But today,
但今天，
you put your sword on my neck
你把剑架在我脖子上
in public.
公开的;当众。
It does not matter that,
没关系，
I had to punish you.
我不得不惩罚你。
Young master, you can stop making excuses.
少爷，你就别再 找借口了。
He had a sudden change of attitude.
他的态度突然转变。
I guess you want to take this opportunity to get rid of Li Ni.
我猜你是想趁这个机会 除掉李妮。
Yeah,
是的，
Why do you trust Li Ni so much?
为什么这么信任李妮？
He harmed the Father to take Changzhou again.
害父复取常州。
The truth is right in front of you.
真相就在你面前。
Why don't you want to be willing to face the truth?
为什么你不愿意 面对事实呢？
TRUE? What is the truth?
真的？真相是什么？
Why does Li Ni want to harm Father?
李妮为什么要害父亲？
In order to retake Changzhou!
为了夺回常州！
I have already ordered my men
我已经命令我的人了
to investigate every detail.
去调查每一个细节。
But now, Li Ni is
但现在，李妮
the biggest suspect.
最大的嫌疑人。
You can't let him go because you want to defend him.
你不能放开他， 因为你想保护他。
Yeah,
是的，
let's drop the topic,
让我们抛开话题吧
Alright?
好吧？
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
你还没吃饭吧？
I have ordered my men to prepare your favorite dishes.
我已经命令我的手下 准备你最喜欢的菜肴了。
You should have something.
你应该有一些东西。
I want to visit Father.
我想去拜访父亲。
Yeah,
是的，
finish your meal,
吃完饭，
and I will take you there.
我会带你去那里。
You are so worried about Father
你很担心父亲
that you can't sleep
你无法入睡
or eat.
或吃。
Father will be worried too
爸爸也会担心
if he sees you in this state, right?
如果他看到你这个样子，对吧？
Young teacher.
年轻的老师。
You guys can go first.
你们可以先走了。
Young master, what about Lieutenant He...
少爷，何中尉呢 ……
Alright.
好吧。
Lieutenant She was deceived and bewitched.
佘中尉被 欺骗了，被迷惑了。
She has reflected on her actions.
她已经反思了自己的行为。
She knows her guilt now.
她现在知道自己的罪孽了。
You can go.
你可以走了。
- Yes Yes.
- 是的 是的。
Padre,
神父，
I will definitely find the culprit
我一定会找到罪魁祸首
behind this incident
这起事件的背后
and get revenge.
并报仇。
Let me stay here and take care of Father.
让我留在这里照顾父亲。
No.
不。
Yeah,
是的，
we are all upset
我们都很沮丧
that Father ended like this.
那个父亲就这样结束了。
We are on high alert as well.
我们也处于高度戒备状态。
I fear that someone is still trying to harm Father.
我担心有人仍然想 伤害父亲。
That's why we came
这就是我们来的原因
with a shift schedule.
有轮班时间表。
Yeah,
是的，
go back to your room
回到你的房间
and sleep.
和睡觉。
I will bring you to see Father
我带你去见父亲
tomorrow morning.
明天早上。
Will you have your words?
你有话要说吗？
Clear.
清除。
In my opinion,
在我看来，
Why don't we load in Changzhou?
为什么不在常州装货？
We can kidnap Great General Cui first.
我们可以先绑架崔大将军。
After that, we can treat it.
之后我们就可以对其进行治疗了。
I will tell them that you were not the one who harmed Great General Cui.
我会告诉他们，害崔大将军的不是你。
Are you stupid?
你是傻子吗？
Yes we did it,
是的，我们做到了，
we have to attack Changzhou first.
我们必须先攻常州。
If we do it,
如果我们这样做，
Mr. Shiqi will never be able to explain himself.
世奇先生永远无法 为自己辩解。
By then, the Cui Army
届时，崔军
He will definitely see us as sworn enemies.
他一定会把我们视为不共戴天的敌人。
Señor Shiqi.
Señor Shiqi.
Taozi.
Taozi.
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Where is your lieutenant?
你的中尉在哪里？
How are you doing?
你好吗？
Lieutenant is arrested.
中尉被捕。
The young master keeps her under heavy surveillance.
少爷对她 严加监视。
I even wanted to lock myself up.
我什至想把自己关起来。
I thought I should escape
我以为我应该逃跑
and come here with your ear.
带着你的耳朵来到这里。
I should regroup with you
我应该和你重聚
and see if there is a way for you to discover the truth.
看看是否有办法让你 发现真相。
Who exactly injured Great General Cui?
到底是谁伤了崔大将军？
Did he have internal injuries?
难道他有内伤？
Or was he poisoned?
还是他中毒了？
It is likely that he was poisoned.
很有可能是中毒了。
What kind of poison?
什么样的毒？
I read his pulse quickly.
我快速地看他的脉搏。
The young master sent his men to arrest me. Before he could figure it out.
少爷派人来抓我。 在他弄清楚之前。
Ying,
英，
my father had a conversation conversation with me
我父亲与我交谈
before he fell unconscious.
在他失去知觉之前。
It allowed me to recognize my ancestry
它让我认清了我的祖先
and changed my name back to Liu Chengfeng.
并把我的名字改 回了刘乘风。
Also he said
他还说
that he was still his son.
他仍然是他的儿子。
Has Father told you?
父亲告诉过你吗？
At first, father thought
起初，父亲以为
you were dead
你死了
I was heartbroken.
我心碎了。
He told me before.
他之前告诉过我。
He thought I was going to disappoint you
他以为我会让你失望
allow you
让你
bear the name Cui Lin
名字叫崔琳
All these years.
这些年来。
Lament
哀叹
that didn't allow you to be your true self.
这不允许你 成为真正的自己。
Father also mentioned one thing.
父亲还提到了一件事。
My father said
我父亲说
would you let me marry you
你能让我嫁给你吗
after changing my name again
再次改名后
a Liu Chengfeng.
a Liu Chengfeng.
My father even said
我父亲甚至说
that our first child
我们的第一个孩子
could take the surname Liu
可以姓刘
while the other children could take
而其他孩子可以采取
the surname Cui.
姓崔。
In this way, both the Cui and Liu family lineage
如此一来， 崔、刘两家的血统
will be preserved.
将被保留。
Yeah,
是的，
father had everything
父亲拥有一切
thought for us.
为我们着想。
It is a shame
这是一种耻辱
que Li Ni
que Li Ni
hurt him
伤害他
before I could do it.
在我能做到之前。
Young master,
少爷，
Are you sure Father said that?
你确定父亲是这么说的吗？
Clear.
清除。
Yeah,
是的，
let's get married.
我们结婚吧。
This way, you will be my wife.
这样，你就是我的妻子了。
And no one will dare
而且没有人敢
mention the incident
提及事件
where you put your sword to my neck again.
你又把剑 抵在我脖子上。
Once
一次
get marry,
结婚，
you can take care of Father properly.
你可以好好照顾父亲。
Father is unconscious
父亲昏迷不醒
and his life is in danger.
他的生命有危险。
Now, do you really want to celebrate a wedding?
现在，你真的想 庆祝婚礼吗？
What if Father regains consciousness?
如果父亲恢复知觉怎么办？
of happiness?
幸福？
It was the Father's disposition.
这是天父的性情。
Yeah,
是的，
are you not willing to do it?
你不愿意做吗？
No, I'm not willing.
不，我不愿意。
My father will not do such
我父亲不会这样做
a fix.
修复。
If you do not believe me,
如果你不相信我，
You can wait until father wakes up.
你可以等爸爸醒来。
You can ask him personally by then.
到时候你可以亲自去问他。
I already told you.
我已经告诉过你。
The father never
父亲从来没有
make such an arrangement!
做出这样的安排！
I guess you've been
我猜你已经
too worried about Father's health
太担心父亲的健康
that you are getting confused.
你感到困惑了。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
I will make arrangements
我会安排
for our wedding.
为了我们的婚礼。
The only thing you have to do now
你现在唯一要做的事
is to become my girlfriend.
就是成为我的女朋友。
Keep an eye on the lieutenant.
密切关注中尉。
Don't let her leave the room.
不要让她 离开房间。
Bring the archers here.
把弓箭手带到这里来。
Maintain strict security.
保持严格的安全。
I don't even want
我什至不想要
see a fly here.
在这里看到一只苍蝇。
- Yes Yes.
- 是的 是的。
Councilor Wang is here.
王议员来了。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Bride,
新娘，
The auspicious hour is approaching.
吉祥时刻即将来临。
you have to dress
你必须穿好衣服
Where is Liu Chengfeng?
Where is Liu Chengfeng?
Tell him to come here.
告诉他到这里来。
Bride,
新娘，
today is your wedding.
今天是你的婚礼。
You are going to marry Young Master Cui soon.
你马上就要嫁给 崔少爷了。
You have no idea how lucky you are.
你不知道自己有多幸运。
Bring Young Master Cui here.
带崔公子过来。
I need to talk to him.
我需要和他谈谈。
But,
但，
I won't let this wedding continue.
我不会让这场婚礼继续下去。
But...
但...
Bring him here!
带他来这里！
Yeah.
是的。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
(Residence of the prefectural governor)
（都道府县知事官邸）
Ying,
英，
Why haven't you dressed yet?
你怎么还没穿好衣服？
It will be horrible
这将是可怕的
if we miss the auspicious hour.
如果我们错过了吉祥的时刻。
It was you.
是你。
It was you, right?
是你吧？
What kind of poison have you fed Father?
你给父亲喂了什么毒？
Look to you.
看你。
Have you forgotten all the joy?
你是否已经忘记了所有的快乐？
Why are you spewing nonsense?
你为什么要胡言乱语？
I was almost killed in Changzhou not long ago.
前不久我在常州差点被杀。
Someone imitated you to attract me.
有人模仿你来吸引我。
However, he only kidnapped me
然而他只是绑架了我
without harming me.
不伤害我。
I thought something was wrong back then.
我当时就觉得出了什么问题。
Was you
是你
who lured me out, right?
谁把我引诱出来的，对吧？
It was you who sent the assassin too, right?
刺客也是你派来的吧？
Ying,
英，
stop spilling nonsense.
别再胡说八道了。
I've been waiting for this day
我一直在等待这一天
since I was a teenager.
从我十几岁起。
Today is our wedding.
今天是我们的婚礼。
You will
你会
my girlfriend soon
我的女朋友很快
Once we get married,
一旦我们结婚了，
I will definitely treat you well.
我一定会好好待你的。
I will also kill Li Ni
我也要杀了李妮
to avenge Father.
为父亲报仇。
Revenge Father, huh?
为父报仇吧？
Liu Chengfeng,
Liu Chengfeng,
You may be able to fool others, but you won't be able to fool me!
你也许能骗得过别人， 但你骗不了我！
It was you who
原来是你
who poisoned the father, right?
谁毒害了父亲，对吗？
Your father always treated you
你的父亲一直对你
like his own son.
就像他自己的儿子一样。
Since young,
从小，
I always treated you like my older brother.
我一直像对待 我的哥哥一样对待你。
How cruel are you
你有多残忍
why do you do something like this?
你为什么要做这样的事？
Yeah,
是的，
mira.
米拉。
I made this pin for you.
我为你做了这个别针。
Today, I finally have the chance
今天，我终于有机会了
give it to him
把这个给他
as my symbol of love.
作为我爱的象征。
Carry it.
携带它。
Yeah,
是的，
It's better that you don't go.
你最好别去。
You could get hurt.
你可能会受伤。
What if Father finds out?
如果父亲知道了怎么办？
that you are hurt?
你受伤了吗？
What if
如果什么
Is there something wrong with you?
你有什么问题吗？
How dare you blackmail me with Father's life?
你竟敢拿 父亲的生命来要挟我？
Father will be happy
爸爸一定会幸福的
as long as you marry me.
只要你嫁给我。
What if something bad happens to Father
如果父亲出了什么不好的事怎么办
Why is he worried about you?
他为什么担心你？
Write immediately!
立即写！
Yeah,
是的，
you should take a break.
你应该休息一下。
I need to invite father
我需要邀请父亲
to witness our wedding too.
也来见证我们的婚礼。
How dare you?
你怎么敢？
Touch Father if you dare!
如果你敢的话，就触摸父亲吧！
Yeah,
是的，
father will be fine
父亲会没事的
as long as you marry me.
只要你嫁给我。
Someone.
有人。
Yes, Young Master.
是的，少爷。
Bring the lieutenant.
带上尉来。
Bring her to the wedding hall
带她走进婚礼殿堂
once the auspicious hour has arrived.
一旦吉祥时刻到来。
Yes, Young Master.
是的，少爷。
- Congratulations, Young Master.
- 恭喜你，少爷。
(Which)
（哪个）
We have to drink until we drop today.
今天我们必须喝到倒下为止。
It is a shame that the Great General has not recovered from his condition.
可惜大将军的 病还没有痊愈。
If not, we will have twice as much happiness.
如果没有，我们将会拥有双倍的幸福。
Padre,
神父，
Today is my wedding with Ying.
今天是我和瑛的婚礼。
Look at all the guests we have here.
看看我们这里的所有客人。
They are all here to congratulate us.
他们都来祝贺我们。
Padre,
神父，
although you are still sick,
虽然你还病着，
I still love you
我依然爱你
to witness our wedding.
见证我们的婚礼。
Padre,
神父，
I have been your son
我曾经是你的儿子
for more than 20 years.
20多年来。
You have never accepted
你从来没有接受过
let me marry Ying.
让我嫁给瑛吧
That's why I can only
这就是为什么我只能
depend on myself
靠我自己
to fulfill my own wish.
来完成我自己的愿望。
Padre,
神父，
I brought you out
我把你带出来了
to show you
给你看
that both the Cui army
那双方崔军
and your precious daughter is mine.
你的宝贝女儿是我的。
Padre,
神父，
hereinafter,
下文中，
I will inherit
我会继承
the empire you built.
你建立的帝国。
I will also ensure
我也会保证
your precious daughter.
你的宝贝女儿。
Shu.
舒。
Lieutenant.
中尉。
Padre,
神父，
I'm going to propose a toast to you.
我要向您敬酒。
After that,
在那之后，
I will marry Ying.
我要嫁给瑛。
Here.
这里。
♪ If I forget the fleeting nature of time ♪
♪ 如果我忘记了时间的短暂 ♪
♪ Wait for the memories ♪
♪ 等待回忆 ♪
♪ smash and sink ♪
♪ 粉碎并沉没 ♪
♪ The emotional scars on your heart ♪
♪ 你心中的情感伤痕 ♪
♪ They are the mess ♪
♪ 他们真是一团糟 ♪
♪ I find it difficult to let go ♪
♪ 我发现很难放手 ♪
♪ If the longing is not forgotten ♪
♪ 如果没有忘记渴望 ♪
♪ I long to return to the first moment ♪
♪ 渴望回到 最初的时刻 ♪
♪ The affection we had in our fateful situation ♪
♪ 我们在命运的处境中所拥有的感情♪
♪ How I wish to keep it for you ♪
♪ 我多么想为你保留它 ♪
♪ If you still remember love ♪
♪ 如果你还记得爱情 ♪
♪ The promises we made ♪
♪ 我们许下的承诺 ♪
♪ Even if this love hurts me ♪
♪ 即使这份爱让我受伤 ♪
♪ I will continue living for you ♪
♪ 我会继续为你而活 ♪
♪ holding on to memories ♪
♪ 紧紧抓住回忆 ♪
♪ Wait it's my persistence ♪
♪ 等等，这是我的坚持 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While waiting for your response ♪
♪ 在等待您的回复时 ♪
♪ If love is remembered ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ Despite going against destiny ♪
♪ 尽管违背命运 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I am willing to sacrifice you ♪
♪ 我愿意牺牲你 ♪
♪ While I wait for your response ♪
♪ 在等待你的回复时 ♪